# Venkat R Siripaati Phone: 91-9398240157

Email: venkatr.siri@gmail.com

#### Flat#B402, Ganesh Prathima Apt, Titwala(W), THANE, 421605.

Over 20 years experience in IT industry and in the area of Manual/ Automation Testing in Agile and Waterfall methodology with leading organizations.

#### **Profile Summary**

Software testing and Quality Assurance professional with excellence in:

@ Software Testing @ Quality Assurance @ S/W Testing Life Cycle

@ Strategy Formulation@ Automation Framework@ Defect Management@ Agile Methodology@ Framework preparation@ Use of Best Practices

@Team Management @ Mobile-Tablets testing @ Performance Engineering

I have worked as Test Engineer (Automation/Manual) for Tata Consultancy Services Ltd from June 2007 to Feb 2015 and currently working as a Test Consultant for SR Future Gateway in Hyderabad (Warangal-STPI). I have gained Finance/Banking domain knowledge like Online Banking and Investment banking sectors during my onsite assignment with **TD Bank, CIBC, ABN AMRO-RBS and Bank of America - Merrill Lynch**. I have also worked with top Insurance providers in US like Humana Inc & Cigna Corp in USA during my onsite assignment.

#### **Education:**

- ❖ Master Of Science in Computer Science from Osmania University in 2001
- ❖ Bachelor Of Science in Computer Science from Osmania University in 1998
- Successfully completed 10+2 computer science in 1995 vocational course (BOE-A.P).

#### **Core Responsibilities:**

- Understand the testing effort by analyzing the requirements of project.
- Estimate and obtain management support for the time, resources and budget required to perform the testing.
- Define the test strategy including test approach, exit criteria and other required details for test management.
- Build a testing team of professionals with appropriate skills, attitudes and motivation.
- Identify Training requirements and forward it to the Project Manager (Technical and Soft skills).
- Develop the test plan for the tasks, dependencies and participants required to mitigate the risks to system quality and obtain stakeholder support for this plan.
- Having knowledge about compliance for HIPAA 270/271 regulations imposed by HHS.
- Having exposure on CAQH Phase 2(CORE) testing for 270/271 Eligibility Benefit Inquiry and Response, validate data in Facets claim engine and FACET data at backend.
- To have a capable of Dental on Facet/Payer system this had built on HIPPA and SOX compliant transactions for 837I/O flow.
- Tested OneWeb Humana site in all the devices (Mobiles, IPAD, Tablets) by using DeviceAnywhere tool
- Assign task to all Testing Team members and ensure that all of them have sufficient work in the project.
- Ensure content and structure of all Testing documents / artifacts is documented and maintained.
- Document, implement, monitor, and enforce all processes for testing as per standards defined by the organization.
- Check / Review the Test Cases documents.
- Keep track of the new requirements / change in requirements of the Project.

- Escalate the issues about project requirements (Software, Hardware, Resources) to Project Manager / Sr. Test Manager.
- Organize the status meetings and send the Status Report (Daily, Weekly etc.) to the Client
- Track and prepare the report of testing activities like test testing results, test case coverage, required resources, defects discovered and their status, performance baselines etc.
- Prepares / updates the metrics dashboard at the end of a phase or at the completion of project.
- Quality Assurance process Improvements or revisions for ISO/CMMI Process guidelines

#### Work Experience:

Dates	Organization	Role
Since Feb 2015 to Till date	S.R Future Gateway Services- Ltd	Test Consultant (Executive Officer)
Since June 2007 to Feb 2015	TATA Consultancy Services, Mumbai.	Test Manager
Since Sept 2006 to June 2007	TCG Software Services Pvt Ltd, Mumbai	Test Manager
Since Feb 2006 to Sept 2006.	IT INTIGRATED SOLUTIONS Ltd, Mumbai.	Test Lead
Since May2004 to Feb 2006	Kalpatharu Computer Services Pvt. Ltd, Mumbai	Sr Test Engineer
Since Feb2002 To May2004.	CCST INFOTECH, Vashi, MB P, Navi Mumbai	Software Developer/Test Engineer
Since Aug 2001 To Feb 2002	COUTH INFOTECH Pvt. Ltd, Hyderabad	Trainee Software Developer/Test Engineer

VersionOne – a version control tool	To track all stories and sprint details including test scripts with test results agile methodology -Used for 2 years.
HP Quality Centre 9.2 &10	More than 5 years of experience

### **Technology-Skill set:**

Technology/Skill set	Learned during academic
TAS-Professional6.0 and VB6.0	Dec 2008 in TCS-MUMBAI
OOPs concepts, JAVA and RDBMS	M.Sc Computer Science in 1998
C, C++ and DBMS	B. Sc Computer Science in 1994
COBAL, BASIC, PASCAL	10+2 Vocational Computer Science in 1992

# **Professional Memberships / Certifications:**

Certified in Performance (Load Runner 8.2) Engineer Level 1-2008	Sept 2008 by TCS EDISON, NJ.
Defect Prevention Prime for Tata Consultancy Services	Dec 2008 by TCS-MUMBAI
	Feb 2007 by TCS-MUMBAI
Internal Auditor (Quality Process)	
ISTQB	Exam-Appeared

# **Project Experience:**

Project#11	SMART HOSPITAL MANAGEMENT SYSTEM
Period	From Feb2015 to till date

Project#11	SMART HOSPITAL MANAGEMENT SYSTEM
Customer	MediLeaf Health Care-HYD
Role	Test Consultant in SRFG-HYDERABAD(STPI-WARANGAL)
Responsibilities	<ul> <li>To read all the documents and understand what needs to be tested.</li> <li>Develop test cases and prioritize testing activities.</li> <li>Execute all the test case and report defects, define severity and priority for each defect.</li> <li>Carry out regression testing every time when changes are made to the code to fix defects.</li> <li>Defining the testing activities for subordinates – test engineers.</li> <li>To check if the team has all the necessary resources to execute the testing activities.</li> <li>To check if testing is going hand in hand with the software development in all phases.</li> <li>Prepare the status report of testing activities and communicate with customers.</li> </ul>
Project Description	SMART HOSPITAL MANAGEMENT SYSTEM  The primary purpose of this project is to integrate all the operations in different departments (Consultation/Laboratory/Pharmacy) in the hospital. Accessing of patient health records among all the departments as per their privileges. Patient can access all his/her health records through internet as well.
Tools/ Languages	LAMP (LINUX, APACHI, MYSQL, PHP) and Selenium 4.0

Project#10	Select EDI (Dental on Facet/Payer)-837I/O flow
Customer	Cigna Corp, USA.
Period	From Jan 2014 to Dec 2014
Role	Test Manager
Responsibilities	<ul> <li>Participating in functional and business requirement walk through and initiate</li> <li>System testing activities.</li> </ul>
	Monitor Integration Testing progress and Prepare E2E integration test scenarios
Description	Dental on Facets: The dental claims (837) are received in the enterprise gateway. The claims are processed through message broker to the FEE EDI middle ware.  Dental on Payer: The dental claims (837) are received in the enterprise gateway. The claims are processed through message broker to the FEE EDI middle ware.
Tools	Share Point 2007, Quality Center, HIPPA Gateway, Sterling and ATM tools for claim submissions. (Selenium tool for testing)
Technologies	TIBCO server, EDI Parser and THG(TriZetto)

Project#9	Claim –Submission- flow (Life Insurance)
Customer	Cigna Corp, USA.
Period	From Aug 2013 to Jan 2014

Role	Test Manager
Responsibilities	<ul> <li>Participating in functional and business requirement walk through and initiate System testing activities.</li> <li>Define the test strategy including test approach, exit criteria and other required details for test management.</li> <li>Monitor Integration Testing progress and Prepare E2E integration test scenarios</li> <li>To verify test data flow with DFD to make sure all the data is flowing correctly and fetching the data as required.</li> </ul>
Description	Claim Flow: Form A module: Filled-up claim form (provided by the insurance company), upload Certificate of death, Policy document, Deeds of assignments/ re-assignments if any, Legal evidence of title (if the policy is not assigned or nominated) and Form of discharge executed and witnessed.
Tools	Share Point 2007, Quality Center, HIPPA Gateway, Sterling and ATM tools for claim submissions.
Technologies	TIBCO server and THG(TriZetto)

Project#8	CAQH (Council for Affordable Quality Healthcare)
Customer	Cigna Corp, USA.
Period	From May 2013 to Aug 2013
Role	Test Manager
Description	CAQH launched the Committee on Operating Rules for Information Exchange (CORE) with the vision of giving providers access to eligibility and benefits information before or at the time of service using the electronic system of their choice for any patient or health plan.
Tools	Share Point 2007, iGate tool, Selenium and Quality Center.
Technologies	TIBCO server, EDI Parser

Project#7	MPSO (Multi Product Sales Origination- Core Banking & Cards)
Period	Oct 2013 to May 2013
Customer	CIBC-Canada
Role	Test Manager in TCS-MUMBAI
Responsibilities	<ul> <li>Analysis the requirements, prepare test plan and design test cases as per for IT requirements.</li> <li>Carry out Quality Assurance activities (reviews, walkthroughs etc.) as defined in the Test Plan.</li> <li>Defect fixing and bug triage meetings for the Defects raised in Quality Centre.</li> <li>Creating different type of Status Reports to present the progress of the project to</li> </ul>

Project#7	MPSO (Multi Product Sales Origination- Core Banking & Cards)
	<ul> <li>the stakeholders.</li> <li>Track effort, timeliness and deviations from the original project schedule</li> <li>Define the test strategy including test approach, exit criteria and other required details for test management.</li> </ul>
	<ul> <li>Build a testing team of professionals with appropriate skills, attitudes and motivation.</li> </ul>
Project Description	Multi Product Sales Origination  The primary goal of this project is to implement cross sales functionality. MPSO Project will help banks to sell multi products recommend with other best fit product based on customer Credit history and liabilities
Tools/ Languages	Quality Center, PEGA and Selenium
Location	TATA Consultancy Services, Mumbai, India

Project#6	GPR-TD Connect				
Period	From Apr 2013 to Oct 2013				
Customer	TD Bank Mount Laurel, NJ, USA				
Role	Test Manager				
Responsibilities	<ul> <li>Define the test strategy including test approach, exit criteria and other required details for test management.</li> </ul>				
	<ul> <li>Build a testing team of professionals with appropriate skills, attitudes and motivation.</li> </ul>				
	<ul> <li>Identify Training requirements and forward it to the Project Manager (Technical and Soft skills). Prepares / updates the metrics dashboard at the end of a phase or at the completion of project.</li> </ul>				
	<ul> <li>Develop the test plan for the tasks, dependencies and participants required to mitigate the risks to system quality and obtain stakeholder support for this plan.</li> </ul>				
	<ul> <li>Defect fixing and bug triage meetings for the Defects raised in Quality Centre.</li> </ul>				
Project Description	GPR/TD Connect:				
	The primary purpose of this project is to launch a General Purpose Reloadable (GPR) card that will help meet two Customer's needs – a complementary card to a existing Checking Account or serve as a new Checking alternative.				
Tools/ Languages	Share Point 2007, Quality Center.				

Project#5	Humana Digital UAT-IDE (Enrolment a Web Portal\Humana.com)				
Customer	Humana Inc, USA.				
Period	From Mar 2010 to Mar 2013				
Role	Agile Test Lead/Scrum Master				
Responsibilities	<ul> <li>Participated in daily stand-up meetings to understand current testing status of the project since we are in agile methodology.</li> </ul>				
	<ul> <li>Participate in all the Sprint planning and Demos sessions (including daily standup) of entire IDE program.</li> </ul>				
	Test Strategy preparation and Prepare E2E integration test scenarios				
	<ul> <li>Prepare test cases-based requirement documents which includes low level and high-level test cases.</li> </ul>				
	Worked on life insurance application Modules.				

	<ul> <li>Uploading all the test cases into VersionOne and Squid as well.</li> <li>We have done mobile testing on multiple OS systems like Android and iOS</li> </ul>
Description	The Integrated Digital Experience initiative aims to integrate Humana's disconnected digital properties, including web, mobile and social, into a best in class, consistent online customer experience and leverage a flexible enterprise technology platform for Medicare-Quoting and Enrolment modules.
Tools	Share Point 2007, Site core, QTP10.0, DeviceAnyWhere, VersionOne and SQUIDS
Technologies	Microsoft visual studio 2010, Microsoft SQL Server 2008

Project# 4	CAP-CASH Administration Application				
Customer	ABN AMRO-RBS (Royal Bank of Scotland) - Netherlands.				
Period	Dec 2009 To Mar 2010				
Description	<ul> <li>Cash Administration application project is planned to provide Cash services to wholesale and global clients of RBS in the Netherlands in collaboration with ABN Amro, Altajo and CiT Companies (Brinks and G4S).</li> </ul>				
Responsibilities	<ul> <li>Involved in Creation of performance test plan</li> <li>Generate Load Runner script and update the script with Correlation an Parameterization</li> <li>Create data flat files for cronjob execution</li> <li>Monitor the performance of the server (CPU Utilization and Memor Utilization)</li> <li>Providing the Recommendations for the good performance etc.</li> <li>Create the Performance test Report with Graphs.</li> </ul>				
Role	Performance Tester (with TCS-PEG Team)				
Solution Environment	J2EE and JSP, Windows Family (Web Based Application)				
Tools	Load Runner 9.2 and Quality Centre				
Highlights	Cap Application tested on 100 concurrent user's Order and Deposit the cash continue 8 hours.				

Project#3	OLB-Online Banking (Internet Channel Technology)				
Customer	Canadian Imperial Bank of Commerce, Toronto-Canada.				
Period	Jul 2009 To Dec 2009				
Role	Test Engineer in TCS-MUMBAI				
Description	CIBC's distributes its products through various channels like Bank's branches, Telephone banking, ABM and Internet channel. Online Banking is one such service offered by internet channel.				
	The <b>Online Banking (OLB)</b> is further divided into 5 customer segments. Each segment is displayed as a separate website and will have significantly different functionality. These segments are:				
	<ul> <li>Retail (Convenience) Banking</li> <li>Small Business Banking</li> <li>Visa Only Banking</li> </ul>				

Project#3	OLB-Online Banking (Internet Channel Technology)			
	<ul><li>Imperial Service Banking</li><li>Private Wealth Management Banking.</li></ul>			

Project#2	SBIMF (State Bank of India Mutual Fund) & JMFMF				
Customer	State Bank of India & JMFMF.				
Role	Software Test Engineer in ITISL LTD				
Period	Jan 2008 To Jun 2008				
Tools	Load Runner 9.2 and Quality Centre				
Project Description	www.Sbimf.com-web portal tested on 100 concurrent users continue 48 hours				

Project#1	DEBOS (Depository Participant BackOffice System)				
Customer	HDFC Bank Ltd, DBI Capital Market Services, Kotak Securities Ltd., BNP Paribas, DSP Merill Lynch.				
Period	Aug2007 To Dec 2007				
Role	Software Test Engineer-Kalpatharu Computer Services				

# **Passport Details**

Name as on passport	Relatio nship	Passport Number	Date of Issue	Expiry Date	Place of Issue
Venkat Raju Siripaati	Self	J1244912	21-Oct-2010	20-Oct-2020	Hyderabad